YONELA SITSHAKA

A 712 Musa road KwaMashu 0769403082 | hopewellsitshaka@gmail.com

ABOUT

I am a self-motivated, creative and innovative person with excellent critical thinking and learning skills which I appreciate improving all the time, I am great at applying my skills both in a team and as an individual.

I am an ICT graduate, who graduated in the class of 2021 at the Durban University Of Technology.

I have gained experience in ERD diagrams, use case Diagram, Microsoft Visio Diagram, GIT, JavaScript, Python with Django and the rest framework, Visual Studio, and Visual studio code, SQL, MySQL database, HTML, C#, MVC asp .net, and word press.

EDUCATION

2019-2021 **DURBAN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY**

KwaZulu-Natal, Durban

Graduation: May 2022

Diploma: Information and Communication Technology in Applications Development

Related Course Work:

Applications Development and Applications Development projects, Information systems, Communication networks, Azure cloud services.

Technical skills: SQL Database, C#, JavaScript, MVC, HTML, Microsoft Visio Diagram, Azure cloud services, UML Modeling

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 - 2023 KZN Sports Confederation

KwaZulu-Natal, Durban

IT Software Development (Intern)

- Developing software for KZN sports confederation to be able to keep all their data online, using Python with Django and the rest framework for APIs, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and MySQL for database
- Worked with the Planners to define requirements and understand them, however, more focused on the backend coding but I am involved throughout the SDLC

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

LIVE SOUND (UNIVERSITY PROJECT)

This project was focused on growing new upcoming artists so they can profit from their work without record labels being the middleman. In this system, they could upload their music for free or choose the sell it there, they also sell other items such as merchandise and so on, and they could receive ratings for their work for feedback and improvement to name a few. I was involved in the backend functionality using C# asp .net MVC framework

DOGPALOUR BOOKING SYSTEM (DONE FOR A FRIEND)

In this project clients booked services for their dogs such as hotel, spa, and dog walk according to the number of services the client purchases they get a deposit. The system admin assigned these tasks to the staff members on the system, and when all the tasks are done a client can rate the services. In this project, I was involved in all the stages of development, from requirement gathering system specification design and development

KZNSC WEBSITE(CURRENT)

MARCH 2022 -2023

THE SYSTEM IS FOR DATA MANAGEMENT AND CAPTURING AT THE KWAZULU-NATAL SPORTS CONFEDERATION FROM THE PROVINCIAL LEVEL TO THE WARD LEVEL, IT WILL ALSO HANDLE ADMINISTRATION AT THE KZNSC AND ITS FEDERATIONS. I AM INVOLVED IN THE BACKEND CODING, ASSISTING IN DEVELOPMENT PHASES FOR EXPERIENCE AND LEARNING

TECHNOLOGIES: PYTHON AND DJANGO REST FRAMEWORK, MYSQL DATABASE.

ADDITIONAL DATA

•

- Skills: fast learning, good communication, creative thinking, problem-solving,
- Technical skills: Front-End Dev, Back-End Dev, Agile Dev, Database design and development
- Programming languages: Python, C#, javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, MySQL, Git , GitHub
- Frameworks: asp .net MVC, Django, Django rest framework
- GitHub account: https://github.com/HopewellA1
- LinkedIn account: linkedin.com/in/yonela-sitshaka-492b26208
- Reference: Solomon (senior software engineer), Peter (Employer)